翻译 NETFLIX　校对 皮带断了
特效 小布　后期&压制 Jason肖
恶魔城
第三季 第８集
你为什么还不睡 已经中午了
Why are you still awake? It's the middle of the day.
我在重新制定我的计划
I'm redrawing my plans.
ZIMUXIA.CN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
你被卡米拉洗脑了
Carmilla's gotten inside your head.
若要让她的计谋成功 我们必须迅速行动
If her scheme is going to work, we need to move fast,
抢在人类重新控制有关地区之前
before the humans regain control over the region in question.
我觉得人类不太可能做到
I don't think that's likely.
瓦拉吉亚的首都一直没有情报传来
There's been no intelligence from the capital of Wallachia.
他们可能正在准备行动
They could be preparing for a move.
也可能都死了
Or they're all dead.
但我不能确定
But I don't know.
所以我必须把这点考虑进去
So I have to factor that in.
你该睡觉了
You should sleep.
我们可以在耗光所有士兵之前
We can possibly push east as far as Lake Balaton
向东推进到巴拉顿湖
before I run out of soldiers,
但那样会暴露我们的西部边境
but that exposes our Western border.
睡吧
Sleep.
只有丽诺尔说服锻造师 我们才能做到
We can't do it without Lenore turning the forgemaster,
而她只是带他出去散他妈的步
and she's just taking him out for fucking walkies.
她会搞定他的
She will land him.
我们行动必须要快
It's going to have to be soon.
上床吧
Come to bed.
还有武器 补给线
And the weapons! The supply lines!
我都计划好了
I worked all that out earlier.
-什么  -只是金钱和时间的问题
- What? - It's just money and time.
我算过了
I did the calculations.
那你算算这个
Then calculate this.
我们需要尸体 但也需要为我们供血的活口
We need dead bodies, but we also need feeding stock.
赫克托能把从这里到巴拉顿湖的所有人类都变成黑暗生物
Hector can make every human from here to Balaton into a night creature,
但那样会让我们失去所有食物
but that leaves us with nothing to eat.
是的
Yes,
但你肯定知道 施第里尔周边地区是如何保卫边界
but surely you know how the regions surrounding Styria defend their borders
对抗城堡中四个可怕的吸血鬼女王的
against the four terrible vampire women in the castle.
用士兵
With soldiers.
他们没那么多士兵
They don't have that many soldiers.
那都是雇佣兵
They hire mercenaries.
好吧 士兵 雇佣兵
Yes. Soldiers, mercenaries,
地方武力...有什么区别呢
local forces... what's the difference?
区别是雇佣兵可以被敌对方
The difference is that mercenaries can be rehired
以更高的价钱雇过来
by the opposing side for more money!
可是... 那样并不光荣
But... there's no honor in that.
确实不光荣 但是有钱
No, but there is money.
所以 我们可以耗尽准备对付我们的力量
So we can deplete the forces rallied against us
按照你的意愿部署我们雇来的人
and deploy the men we buy, as you wish.
你真能办到吗
You can actually do this?
这是一个行政问题 而且我已经解决了
It was an administrative problem, and I solved it.
你们就不能小声点吗
Can you not keep it down?
我隔着几堵墙和三个打鼾的男孩 都能听见你们说话
I can hear you through several walls and three snoring boys.
我不想知道
I do not want to know.
你们大中午的在做什么啊
What are you doing in the middle of the bloody day?
完善你的计谋
Making your scheme work.
它不需要"完善" 本来就很高明
You don't have to "make" it work. It was bloody genius.
早上好 我要去睡了
Good morning. I'm going to bed.
既然现在大家都醒了 不如一起喝一杯
Well, we're all awake now, we might as well have a drink.
你可以告诉我 你是怎么完善我的计谋的
And you can tell me how you helped with my scheme.
等等
Wait.
你说那是"计谋"
You call it a scheme?
就是计谋
It is a scheme.
无礼
Rude.
但你坚持的话...我们可以喝一杯
But if you insist... we can have a drink
然后告诉你 我们将如何在明年统治一个帝国
and tell you how we'll be ruling an empire next year.
前提是丽诺尔能完成她的任务
If Lenore can do her part.
现在我必须喝一杯了
Well, now I definitely need a drink.
她就像他妈的收养了他一样
I think she's fucking adopted him.
他有事瞒着我们 你知道吗
He's holding things back from us, you know.
他很孤独 想让我们留下来
He's lonely. He wants us to stay.
但他确实杀了他的父亲
Well, he did kill his father.
以及帮他离开的人
And the people who helped him left.
就他自己在一座死城堡中守卫一间破房子
It's just him in a dead castle guarding a ruined house.
这似乎不公平 对吧
It doesn't seem fair, does it?
他除掉了德古拉的世界 只得到这样的回报
He rid the world of Dracula, and this is his reward.
我觉得他认为自己活该
I think that he thinks he deserves it.
孤独吗
The loneliness?
他杀了自己的亲生父亲
He killed his own father.
他想为此受罚
He wants to be punished for it.
虽然他没有其他选择
Even though he had no choice.
看样子 他可能也杀了阿町
It seems that he probably killed Cho, too.
至少阿町是因为他袭击德古拉而死
At the very least, Cho died as a result of his attack on Dracula.
现在家乡比以往任何时候都更不受保护了
Now home is more unprotected than ever.
但他有太多神奇的东西
But he has so many wonderful things.
他能为我们做很多 给我们一个未来
He can do so much for us. Give us a future.
但他留在这
But he stays here
是因为在不自杀的情况下
because it's as close to death as he can manage
这是最接近死亡的方式了
without killing himself.
我们应该为他做点什么
We should do something for him.
给他一个奖励
Give him a reward.
先让我睡一觉好吗
Can it be after I've had a nap?
我看了很多书 头痛死了
I've read so much, my brain hurts.
你真懒
So lazy.
不是懒
I'm not lazy.
只是为重要工作保留体力
I conserve my resources for important efforts.
比如吃饭
Like eating?
天啊 我们是不是没吃午饭
God, did we miss lunch?
也许阿鲁卡多可以再做一顿午饭
Maybe Alucard can make lunch again.
-还有晚饭  -再做一顿晚饭吗
- And dinner. - One more dinner?
其实早晚有一天 我又得开始自己做饭了
Well, sooner or later, I'll have to start preparing my own food again.
别人做的饭味道更好
And meals taste better when someone else makes them.
我经常这么说
That's what I always say.
我知道
I know.
那好吧
All right, then.
午饭和晚饭
Lunch and dinner,
看看晚上的情况再说
and we'll see what the night brings.
该死
Shit.
你又在到处乱走吗
Are you wandering around again?
不是 完全不是
N-n-no, not at all.
我只是在出去之前活动活动腿脚
Just stretching my legs before I go outside.
这膝盖已经不如从前了
The knees, you know. Not what they used to be.
我花了太多时间蹲着看你那些精彩绝伦的书
I spent too much time crouching down with your wonderful books.
这样啊
I see.
说真的 很精彩
H-Honestly. Wonderful.
我学习到很多东西
I've learned so much.
你... 学习到了什么
What... have you learned?
我相信这个地方以前的居住者中有很多人
Well, I believe many of the previous occupants of this place
对接触地狱本身有着真正的兴趣
had a real interest in contacting Hell itself.
你是说我们不是...我是说...
You mean we are not the... I mean...
以前就发生过吗
this has happened before?
过去就有吗
In the past.
我清楚地了解到曾有人试图
It's clear to me that there have been attempts
在这打开一扇地狱之门
to open a door to Hell here.
事实上 整个修道院都可能被污染了
In fact, this entire structure could be contaminated.
我担心你们的健康 萨拉
I worry for your health, Sala!
我本人已经出现了讨厌的咳嗽和轻微的跛行
I myself may have developed a nasty cough and a slight limp.
你们不该留在这里
You shouldn't be here.
我们有两位修道士失踪了
Two of our number have gone missing.
但我们的工作就快完成了
But our work is almost done here.
不够快 萨拉
Not soon enough, Sala!
他们可能被遍布在这座建筑
They may have expired from the Satanic poison
石木中的撒旦的毒药毒死了
permeating the very stones and timbers of this building.
我们现在不能走
We can't leave right now.
但你必须走 快逃吧 萨拉
But you must! You must flee, Sala!
逃
Flee?
说得对 院长 就是逃
You're absolutely right, Prior! Flee!
那么...
So...
不如你告诉我 修道院里有多少人
why don't you tell me how many of you there are in that priory?
你来晚了
You're a bit late.
不像从前那么多了 但也足够了
Not as many as there used to be, but more than enough.
怎么 你们在里面互相残食吗
What, have you been eating each other in there or something?
一直有人离开... 已经好几天了
We've been leaving... for days!
就我们几个人 一天出去一个
Just a few of us, one a day.
走到其他城镇 传播消息
Walking to other towns, spreading the word.
-像感染一样  -像福音传教士一样
- Like an infection. - Like evangelists.
传播知识和计划
Passing on the knowledge and the plan.
把地狱带到这个被遗弃的世界上
Bring Hell to this abandoned Earth.
这是萨拉的计划吗
This is Sala's plan?
这是我们访客的计划
This is our Visitor's plan.
他对我们说话了
He spoke to us.
我们在脑子里听见了他的声音
We heard his voice in our heads.
从那一刻起
Since that moment,
一切都无比清晰了
everything has been clear.
黑暗生物果然让他们疯掉了
It really did drive them insane.
也许修道士们才是这里的受害人
The monks may actually be the victims here.
黑暗生物有魔力 可能扭曲了他们的思想
Night creatures have magical powers. It may have distorted their minds.
修道院地下有一个黑暗生物
They've got a night creature under the priory.
他们没杀它 而是把它藏起来了
They didn't kill it, they hid it.
等等 等一下
Wait. One second.
继续说
Carry on.
修道院已成一片废墟
The priory is in ruins.
我怀疑那里已经不圣洁了
I suspect it's been deconsecrated.
地下室关着一个黑暗生物
There is a night creature being held on a basement level,
它周围画着符号
symbols drawn around it.
回廊也在那个地下室
The Corridor is in that same basement.
它在那里活着的吗
It's alive down there?
是的 我都没感觉到它有痛苦
Yes! I didn't even get the sense that it was in pain.
而且它离回廊的距离近得可疑
And it's proximity to the Corridor is suspicious.
我觉得它在等待
I think it's waiting.
萨拉和他的人在制定某种计划
Sala and his men are enacting some kind of plan
其中涉及这些炼金术符号
involving these alchemical symbols.
我们见过的那些符号吗
The same symbols we've seen?
没错 符号组合
Indeed! Combined!
修道院老图书馆的书卷缺了几页
There are pages missing from volumes in the priory's old library.
炼金术的用途果真令人着迷
The application of alchemy is honestly f-fascinating.
他们完全忽略了修道院藏书中最精彩的部分
They completely ignored the best part of the books stored in the priory.
两个经历过死亡和重生的人
Two persons who have gone through death and rebirth
可被融成同体者
can be fused into The Rebis,
炼金术的终极目标
the ultimate alchemical goal,
-他们连想都没想过...  -圣日耳曼 别跑题
- and they didn't even think of it... - Saint Germain. Focus.
好...好的 当然
Y-Yes, yes, of course.
只是错过了完成炼金术的机会
It's just, the missed opportunity to complete alchemy itself!
那能拯救全世界
It could save the very world!
先拯救这个小镇吧
Let's settle for saving this town.
没错 我觉得我像是被引领来这里的
Indeed. I feel as if I've been led here.
就为找到无限回廊
To find the Infinite Corridor,
实现哲学的终极目标
to achieve the ultimate goal of philosophy,
而且成为... 英雄
and to be... a hero.
从一个谨慎而恭敬的...距离
From a discreet and respectful... distance.
我们完蛋了
We're doomed.
绝对没有
We absolutely are not.
赛珐 请你给我翻译一下这个白痴的胡言乱语
Sypha, translate this idiot's gibberish into actual language for me.
我还没掌握足够的信息
I don't have enough information yet.
你只需要知道 修道院不再圣洁了
All you need to know is that the priory is desecrated
而且他们在以某种方式和一个活的黑暗生物合作
and they are somehow working with a living night creature
它教会了他们魔法
who has taught them magic.
遗憾的是 这完全有可能
Sadly, that is all entirely possible.
我们能应付那个黑暗生物
We can handle the night creature,
但我不想先干翻一小群疯狂的僧修道士
but I'd rather not wade through a small army of mad monks to get to it.
我会分阶段召集我的武装
I'll summon my men-at-arms by stages.
我不想引起恐慌或被萨拉发现
I don't want to cause alarm or give Sala warning.
我们在日落时进攻 到时候镇民们都在家里
We'll strike at sundown, when the townsfolk will be indoors.
赛珐和圣日耳曼得跟我去修道院地下
Sypha and Saint Germain will need to get under the priory with me.
你的人绝对不能靠近那里
Your people shouldn't be anywhere near that.
给我们挖个洞 拦住所有修道士
Make a hole for us, and keep the monks off our backs.
我们真的有时间等到日落吗
Do we really have time to wait for sundown?
这是我的镇子 你们听我指挥
This is my town. You do as I say.
我们必须讲战术 以人多取胜
We must have strategy and force of numbers.
妥善完成才行
This will be done properly.
我去准备了
I'll begin the preparations.
话说 我为什么要跟你们一起下去
And, why would I be going down there with you?
我好像没听见你宏伟大计的那部分
I seem to have missed that part of your epic plan.
因为据你所说
Because from what you've said,
你和无限回廊之间有一只黑暗生物
there's a night creature between you and the Infinite Corridor.
是啊...
Yes...?
我们可能只有一次机会
And we may only have one chance
让你通过 这样你就可以打开回廊
to get you past it so you can open the Corridor.
我好像没太听懂...
I'm afraid I don't understa...
等等
Wait!
你是...你是在在...帮我吗
You're... You're actually... helping me?
你真是...好人
You're being... kind.
好了 好了 没必要大惊小怪
All right, all right, no need to make a production out of it.
好吧...很抱歉
Well... I'm so sorry.
我只是不习惯别人无缘无故对我好
I'm-I'm-I'm simply not used to people being kind to me for no reason.
够了 小声点
That's enough. Keep it down.
别让任何人听见
We don't want anyone to hear.
有一次他看到一个男人想踢一只猫
He saw a man try to kick a cat once,
结果他把那个男人的腿打折了三个地方
and he broke the man's leg in three places!
不能随便踢猫 不是吗
Well, you don't do that to cats, do you?
三处骨折 我听见三声
Three places. I heard three cracks.
可怜的猫咪 它又没害谁
Poor bloody cat wasn't hurting anyone.
猫咪只想好好活着
Cats just want to get on with their lives.
你为我们展示了真相
You have shown us the truth.
我们听了你的话 做好了准备
We have listened. We have prepared.
如你所愿 我们禁锢了你
We have restrained you, as you wished.
也照你的意思给了你沉思的时间
We have given you time to meditate, as you asked.
上帝遗弃了这个世界
God has abandoned the Earth.
德古拉必须被复活
Dracula must be brought back.
这是你的目的
It is what you want.
也是你的锻造师的目的
It is what he who forged you would want.
我们以访客及其锻造师...
We do this in the name of our Visitor,
艾萨克之名这样做
and his forgemaster, Isaac.
日落之时
When the sun goes down,
我们就做该做之事
we shall do what needs to be done.
这里的军械库很漂亮
The armory here is beautiful.
不过 我以为会有更神奇的武器
I expected there to be more magical weapons, though.
我父亲是一位技艺高超的魔法师
My father was an accomplished magician.
他本身力量强大
He held enough power within himself
所以觉得魔法增强武器是不必要的
that he felt magically enhanced weapons to be unnecessary.
他喜欢让物质保持原样
He preferred physical things to be themselves.
你呢
Do you?
我没有强烈的观点
I don't have a strong opinion.
我认为魔法和科学是同一枚硬币的两面
Magic and science are two sides of the same coin to me.
你确定城堡能移动吗
Are you sure the castle can't be moved?
确定
I'm sure.
你没隐瞒我们什么吧
There's not something you're not telling us?
没有
No.
如果你对我们有所隐瞒 会告诉我们吗
Would you tell us if there's something you're not telling us?
你说什么
Excuse me?
只是...
It's just that...
城堡的某些部分 你故意不让我们看
there are parts of the castle that you avoid showing us.
有些事你从来不谈
Things you don't talk about.
城堡很大
It's a big castle.
到处都是像密室这样的老建筑
Filled with centuries of material, like the Hold.
我们在一起的时间多着呢 不是吗
We have plenty of time together, don't we?
是的
Yes, we do.
那好吧
All right, then.
谁饿了
Who's hungry?
夜幕已经降临了吗
Has night fallen already?
-你没听见我进来  -没有
- You didn't hear me enter. - No.
你有一股气味
You have a scent.
就像... 茉莉花和葡萄酒
Like... jasmine and wine.
很棒的书吗
Good book?
以前我没注意到这枚戒指
I didn't notice that ring before.
真的吗 我们都戴着
Really? We all wear them.
都
All?
我们四个
The four of us.
卡米拉 莫拉娜 斯崔格和我
Carmilla, Morana, Striga and I.
我猜这其中一定有什么令人不安的原因
I'm presuming there's some disturbing reason for that
而且我会后悔问起
and I will regret asking.
傻瓜
Silly.
看 黑色和红色
Look. The black and the red.
代表黑夜和鲜血
The night and the blood.
正是它们让我们聚在一起
These are the things that bind us together.
戒指是忠于彼此的标志
The rings are a sign of loyalty to each other.
真是...好吧
That's actually... well,
"美好"这个词似乎不合适
"nice" seems like the wrong word.
就是美好
It is nice.
看来这是你们的另一面
It's a different facet of you all, I suppose.
就像这本书
Like this book.
是啊
Yes.
这是一本魔法著作 但也是...
It's a magical work, but it's also...
该怎么形容呢
how to describe it?
吸血鬼哲学 真是令人着迷
Vampire philosophy. It's fascinating.
那现在我们不全是恶魔了吗
So now we're not all monsters?
我没那么说
I didn't say that.
好了 承认吧
Go on, admit it.
我承认这比我想象的更有...
I admit there seems to be more...
深度...
depth to...
该叫什么呢
what would you call it?
吸血鬼文化吗
Vampire culture? Than I thought.
这里有关于世界实体存在的观点
There are ideas in here about physical presence in the world,
土壤 景观和生命的
the importance of soil and landscape
...重要性
and... being.
其实是哲学 不可思议
I mean, actual philosophy. Amazing.
那就好
Well, good.
那我有一个哲学问题想问你
Then I have a philosophical question for you.
好
All right.
当另一个人在笼子里时 很难进行外交
It's hard to do diplomacy when the other person is in a cage.
我无法反驳
I can't disagree.
外交就是妥协
Diplomacy is compromise.
我获得一些好处 你获得一些好处
I get something, you get something.
虽然你我都没得到想要的全部的一切 但都能快乐地离开
Neither of us get everything we want, but we both leave happy.
-我洗耳恭听  -但是你...
- You have my attention. - But you...
你连离开的机会都没有
you don't even get to leave!
你什么都没得到
You haven't got anything!
所有权力都在我手上 你只是笼子里的英俊男子
I have all the power, and you're a pretty man in a box.
我... 英俊吗
I'm... I'm pretty?
看起来不公平
It just doesn't seem fair.
怎么回事
What's happening?
我一天没睡 一直在想这件事
I've been awake all day thinking about it.
你 待在这里
You. Down here.
你要问的是什么 丽诺尔
What's the question, Lenore?
你想要什么
What do you want?
我想被放出去
I want to be let out.
我知道
I know.
我只能想到这个
That's all I can think of.
这是我唯一能为你做的事
It's the only thing I can do for you.
但你不会直接放我走
But you're not just gonna let me out.
嗯...是不会
Well... no.
我忠于我的姐妹们
I'm loyal to my sisters.
不会打开门说 "飞吧 给你自由 英俊的人类男孩"
To just fling open the door and say, "Fly, be free, pretty human boy"?
那...那是赤裸裸的背叛
That... That would be a direct betrayal.
过来坐下
Come and sit down.
而且 你一个人活不过一天
Also, you'd survive less than a day on your own.
才不会
That's not true.
好吧 你说得很对
Well, OK, that's completely true
我可能马上就死掉了
and I would die almost immediately.
在整个谈判中 你只有一个优势
You only have one advantage in this whole negotiation.
我不知道这是不是优势
I'm not sure it's an advantage.
我喜欢你
I like you.
这不是我以为你要说的话
That wasn't what I was expecting to hear.
那你以为你的优势是什么
Well, what did you think your advantage was?
你想让我用魔法
You want me to do my human magic
给卡米拉建造一支怪物大军
to give Carmilla an army of monsters.
那个啊
That.
白天我偷听了莫拉娜和斯崔格的对话
I was eavesdropping on Morana and Striga during the day.
她们可以收买雇佣军来充实军队
They can buy mercenaries to fill out the army.
我不明白 卡米拉放弃了吗
I don't understand. Carmilla's given up?
她分神了
She gets distracted.
她称之为"天才的负担"
She calls it the burden of genius.
就算我们今早遗弃她 她也会好几天都发现不了
We could run out on her this morning and she wouldn't notice for days.
我忠于我的姐妹们...
I'm loyal to my sisters...
但我们的做法并不对
but what we're doing is wrong.
我们可以离开 赫克托
We could just leave, Hector.
如果你想跟我在一起
If you want to be with me.
我想知道...
I was wondering...
应该怎么打开无限回廊
how does someone open the Infinite Corridor?
那是一种令人震惊的意志行为
It's an appalling act of will.
既要古老的知识 又要牺牲你灵魂的一部分
A combination of ancient knowledge and sacrificing something of your soul.
即使这样 也没办法精确控制
And it's still impossible to control with any accuracy.
但你能做到
But you can do it.
上次开门 我花了一年时间才恢复
It took me a year to recover from the last time I did it.
我们能确定修道士们真的不知道回廊的入口在下面吗
And we're sure the monks don't know an entrance to the Corridor is down there?
绝对不知道 人眼看不见
Absolutely. It's invisible to the human eye.
所以我需要宝石
It's why I need the jewel.
我想我们犯了一个严重的错误
I think we've made a terrible mistake.
萨拉
Sala!
萨拉院长
Prior Sala!
当你只是一个单纯的修道士的时候
When you were a simple man of the church,
我容忍了你对我的人民的控制
I tolerated your hold on my people.
当你成了躲避人民的疯狂隐士时 我依然容忍了你
When you became a mad hermit who shunned my people, I tolerated you still.
现在不行了
No more.
你必须让出修道院 出来的时候扔掉武器
You will vacate the priory. Throw your weapons out as you exit.
萨拉 我知道你已经亵渎了修道院
Sala! I know you have deconsecrated the priory.
上帝已经不在里面了
God is no longer in that house.
没有谁保护你
You enjoy no protection.
出来 全部出来
Out! All of you! Now!
不然我们就进去了 萨拉
Or we come for you, Sala!
ZIMUXIA.CN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
时辰已到
It is time.